In the model, there are n companies and a subpopulation S of up to N agents. Each company has a capacity to host C agents from S. Each agent has a preference ranking and a binary minority variable. The preference ranking is a ranking of five hypothetical companies with the proportional share of minorities employed being 0, ¼, ½, ¾ and 1. The minority dummy indicates whether the agent itself is a minority group member. A total of T agents are sampled randomly and consecutively one by one from an infinite population P of some distribution of preference rankings and minorities, and added to S.

For each agent x added to S, the companies are assigned inverse utilities based on their proportional share of minorities, rounded to the closest quartile, and the preference rankings of x. The agent x is assigned to the company with the highest utility, or randomly to one of them in case of a tie. If there are more than N agents in S, then one random agent is removed from S (and the company it was assigned to).

After T rounds, the index of dissimilarity d, that is, the proportional ratio of agents that would have to move to a different company in order to match the proportion of minorities in S, is computed. Let W and B be the total number of majority and minority group agents in S, respectively, and let w_i and b_i be the number of majority and minority group agents at company i, respectively. The index of dissimilarity is:

d= 1/2 ∑_(i=1)^n | b_i / B - w_i / W | 
